SURAJ PIPARIYA



CONTACT

Phone:

+91 9420021118

Email:

SurajPipariya@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

linkedin.com/in/surajpipariya/

Certification

Power BI Data Analyst
Tableau Data Analyst
Pursuing DP-600: Implementing
Analytics Solutions Using Microsoft
Fabric

Education

Vishwakarma Institute of technology, Pune

Master of Computer Application [July 2014 – June 2017]

G.H. Raisoni Institute of Information Technology, Nagpur

Bachelor of Computer Application [July 2010 – June 2013]

Technical Skills & Tools

Database operation: SQL Server Management Studio, SAP

Programming: SQL, JS, Asp.net, Webservices, Html, Css, Bootstrap.

Tools: Power BI, Tableau, Alteryx, Wordpress, Google Analytics.

ABOUT

Solutions - oriented Data & Power BI Analyst with proven expertise analyzing various large datasets for the e-commerce, healthcare and financial industries. Proficiency in grasping new technical concepts quickly and productively utilizing them. Versatile, quick-learner, willing to embrace new challenges.

EXPERIENCE

Viatris Inc. - Pharmaceutical & Healthcare

Data Analyst | Pune | June 2022 - Ongoing

- As part of data analytics team, I have designed and build 22 reports out of 52 reports for ecommerce and manufacturing reporting suite.
- Collaborated with subject matter experts to define data requirements and source-to-target mapping necessary to support advanced analytics initiatives for on-boarding 27 B2B ecommerce sites on reporting suite.
- Led the development of site specific automated Power BI reports using complex dax calculations, bookmarks, selection panes, and drill through filters which are embedded in PowerPoint for monthly review by BA's.
- Build customized **Usage Metric** report based for past data view more than **30**days using Power BI dataset, Power Apps and SharePoint list.
- Designed and build **Data Catalogue** tool in Power BI for superusers to view data lineage of fields from Source>Data warehouse>Power BI Reports including sample data available in tables and fields.
- Developed Admin dashboard in Power BI for internal stake holders to track and manage reporting request, issue ledger and approval cockpit with in-report data updating functionality using embedded Power App.
- Provided continued maintenance and development of bug fixes for existing and new Power BI reports every 3 months as part of reporting release.

Siemens Technologies

Data Analyst | Pune | March 2021 – Jan 2022

- Consult and build solutions to improve financial process and provide reporting solutions for Siemens headquarter team.
- **Financial Reporting** includes Briefing dashboard, Bid Process Analytics, Merger & Acquisitions, ORCA (Order Recognition & Contract Analysis)
- Analyzed business problems & prepared Power BI reports using DAX calculations, bookmarks, KPI based alerts for meaningful insights.
- Preparing dashboard using calculations, parameters in Tableau, LOD expressions, data blending, etc. using SQL Server & SAP data source.
- Requirement gathering, specification implementation, organizing UAT, support product upgrades & enhancing existing functionalities

Eaton Technologies

Data Analyst | Pune | June 2019 - Feb 2021

- Build complex Power BI dashboards from a multisite Ecommerce data warehouse to provide insightful analysis and identify growth opportunities, which are used by FA's and BA's of 68 ecommerce stores.
- Experience on building a modern BI solution giving insights at KPI level and a detailed dashboard about each KPI for internal stakeholders.
- Experience on working with SQL Server, Google Analytics, and excel sheets as data source used in our BI solution.
- Effectively interacted with BA's for ecommerce store setup as onboarding of new stores with Oracle Commerce and ATG.
- Daily monitoring & troubleshoot of e-commerce platforms to ensure data is complete and accurate.